Design.]

Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Embedded Systems and

Ritesh Deelip Sonawane Featured



Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C, Assembly, Shell Scripting, C++, Data Structure, Algorithm, GDB, Valgrind, GIT, Visual Studio, NVMe, SMBus, I2C



Current Designation: Software Engineer -Software

Development

Current Company: Toshiba software India Pvt Ltd.

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Noida Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Maintenance, Project

Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C, Assembly, Shell Scripting, C++, Data

Structure, Algorithm, GDB, Valgrind, GIT, Visual Studio, NVMe, SMBus, I2C

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Over 4.8 years of extensive experience in complete software development life cycle, Requirements collection, Design, Development, Testing, Debugging, Maintenance and Enhancement.

Worked on Implementation of memory management related system call, memory allocator, system applications for Linux based operating system.

Having an excellent understanding of Linux memory management, file systems.

Proficient in C language, Data structures and good knowledge of shell scripting.

Good Understanding of MCTP Over SMbus/I2C protocol.

Work Experience

Toshiba software India Pvt Ltd. as Software Engineer -Software Development

Aug 2020 to Till Date

PROJECT 3: Enterprise SSD (SSD FIRMWARE) (Aug 2020 - Currently Working)

Company: Toshiba software India pvt ltd. Environment: CM5/CD5 (NVMe SSD)

Description: Project is to develop firmware for CM5(Enterprise NVMe SSD) and CD5 (Data center SSD) as generic model

or

customize model.

Responsibilities:

Understand and implement various customization requirements for MCTP over SMBus protocols.

Analyze and fix the customer reported issues.

Ensure the robustness of developed code on SM Bus using I2C Exerciser and Analyzer.

Eximius Design India (Pvt.) Ltd, as Software Engineer

Oct 2019 to Aug 2020

PROJECT 2: CLOVER (SSD FIRMWARE) (OCT 2019 - Aug 2020)

Company: Eximius Design India (Pvt.) Ltd, Bangalore.

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=eadaebb5ad604489438203a1bb970d990d580b541c110a440b40175a5...

Client : W estern Digital, Bangalore. Environment : 2TB M.2 NVMe drives/SSD

Description: Clover is the project to upgrade the existing SSD firmware for BiSC4 x4 Generation of NAND along with new

features to enhance the Read/write performance and data retention of SSD drives.

Responsibilities

Handling the different requirements at the physical layer of SSD drive firmware. Giving support for power management (Low power state) at the physical layer.

Responsible for Sanity and regression testing on Model and Hardware environment.

HCL Technology as Software Developer

Mar 2016 to Oct 2019

PROJECT 1: NEC-HPC OS (VEOS - Linux kernel based OS) (March 2016 - OCT 2019)

Company: H CL Technology, Noida Client: N EC Technology, Japan

Environment: N EC SX-Aurora, x86 and CentOS.

Description: NEC-HPC OS is the project to develop Linux kernel based Operating system (VEOS) for vector computers (N

EC

SX-Aurora TSUBASA) designed by NEC Technology. SX-Aurora TSUBASA is provided as a PCIe card, termed by NEC

as

"Vector Engine (VE)".

Responsibilities:

Development for various memory related system call and Buddy memory allocator by studying the Linux Kernel implementation.

Development of API for physical memory allocation, virtual memory management.

Debugging, testing for developed function and system calls.

Handling and providing solutions for various issues reported by customers.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Government College of Engineering (GCE), Pune in 2014

PG: PG Diploma (Embedded Systems and Design.) from CDAC, Pune in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma (Electronics & Telecommunication)

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version Last Used | Experience |
|-----------------------------------|-------------------|------------|
| CentOS, Kali, Ubuntu, Windows | | |
| Unix, Linux | | |
| C, Assembly, Shell scripting, C++ | | |
| Data structure, Algorithm | | |
| GDB, Valgrind, GIT | | |
| VISUAL STUDIO | | |
| Metaware, Source Insight | | |
| I2C, NVMe, SMBus | | |

Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English | | | | |

| 1 | 1/22/2021 | https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=eadaebb5ad604489438203a1bb970d990d580b541c110a440b40175a5 | | |
|---|-----------|---|--|--|
| | Hindi | | | |

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Marathi

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time